Charles B. Davenport Papers ca.1903-1940 Mss.B.D27
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Charles B. Davenport Papers, 1878-1944; 43 linear feet (Box 1-97)
  - Shaler, N. S. (Box 85)
  - Shambaugh, George E. (Box 85)
  - Shannon, Howard J. (Box 85)
  - Shapiro, H. L. (Box 85)
  - Sheep Records (Box 85)
    - Sheep Records - Alexander Graham Bell, 1904 (Box 85)
    - Sheep Records - Durham, New Hampshire, 1915; 2 folders (Box 85)
  - Sheldon, E. S. (Box 85)
  - Sheldon, H. H. (Box 85)
  - Shelford, V. E. (Box 85)
  - Shelton, Butler (Box 85)
  - Shepard, Charles E. (Box 85)
  - Shepperd, J. H. (Box 85)
  - Sherbon, Florence B., 1924-1927; 2 folders (Box 85)
    - Folder 1 (Box 85)
    - Folder 2 (Fitter Families Exam Forms) (Box 85)
  - Sherman, H. C. (Box 85)
  - Sherwood, George H. (Box 85)
  - Shipley, A. E. (Box 85)
  - Shreve, Forrest (Box 85)
  - Shull, A. Franklin (Box 85)
  - Shull, Charles Albert (Box 85)
  - Shull, George Harrison, 1904-1956; 14 folders (561 items) (Box 85-86)
    Biographical and personal data; Botany and plant genetics; Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington -- Burbank, Luther; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Editorial matters -- Genetics; Eugenics; Genetics of plants -- Bursa; Genetics of plants -- Oenothera; Graduate study; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Third Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Fifth Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Travel -- Germany; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - Folder 1, 1904-1906 (Box 85)
    - Folder 2, 1907-1908 (Box 85)
    - Folder 3, 1909-1911 (Box 85)
    - Folder 4, 1912-1914 (Box 85)
    - Folder 5, 1915 (Box 85)
    - Folder 6, 1916-1917 (Box 86)
    - Folder 7, 1918-1919 (Box 86)
    - Folder 8, 1920 (Box 86)
    - Folder 9, 1921 (Box 86)
    - Folder 10, 1922 (Box 86)
    - Folder 11, 1923-1924 (Box 86)
    - Folder 12, 1925-1926 (Box 86)
    - Folder 13, 1927-1930 (Box 86)
    - Folder 14, 1934-1956 (Box 86)
  - Shurtleff, Arthur A. (Box 86)
  - Siegenthaler-Krebs, Mina (Box 86)
  - Siegfried, André (Box 86)
  - Siemens, Hermann W. (Box 86)
  - Sigerfoos, Charles P. (Box 86)
  - Simpson, Jennie L. S. (Box 86)
  - Simpson, Jesse T. (Box 86)
  - Skelinska, Maria (Box 86)
  - Skinner, Charles E. (Box 86)
  - Skinner, Clarence E. (Box 86)
  - Skogsberg, Tage (Box 86)
  - Skrainka, Philip (Box 86)
  - Slade, D. D. (Box 86)
  - Slossen, E. E. (Box 86)
  - Small, Albion W. (Box 86)
  - Small, W. S. (Box 86)
  - Smallwood, Mabel E. (Box 86)
  - Smallwood, W. M. (Box 86)
  - Smith, A. O. (Box 86)
  - Smith, Audrey N. (Box 86)
  - Smith, Bertram G. (Box 86)
  - Smith, Carrie W. (Box 86)
  - Smith, Erwin F. (Box 86)
  - Smith, Frank (Box 86)
  - Smith, Franklin S. (Box 86)
  - Smith, G. Byron (Box 86)
  - Smith, H. W. (Box 86)
  - Smith, James Perrin (Box 86)
  - Smith, Longfield (Box 86)
  - Smith, Lybrand P. (Box 86)
  - Smith, Theobald (Box 86)
  - Smithsonian Institution (Box 86)
  - Snell, George D. (Box 86)
  - Snelling, Walter O. (Box 86)
  - Snow, Laetitia Morris (Box 86)
  - Snyder, Lawrence H., 1921-1936; 3 folders (101 items) (Box 86)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics -- Fifth Congress; Ohio State University; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1921-1927 (Box 86)
    - Folder 2, 1928-1933 (Box 86)
    - Folder 3, 1934-1936 (Box 86)
  - Snyder, Mrs. Reginald Clare (Box 87)
  - Society for Relief of Half-Orphan and Destitute Children. (Box 87)
  - Society of Physical Anthropology (Box 87)
  - Society of St. Johnsland (Box 87)
  - Sonneberg, Walter (Box 87)
  - Soper, George A. (Box 87)
  - Sosman, Robert B. (Box 87)
  - Soulsby, Basil H. (Box 87)
  - Southall, James P. C. (Box 87)
  - Southard, E. E. (Elmer Ernest), 1909-1920; 3 folders (118 items) (Box 87)
    Eugenics Record Office; Evolution; Human genetics; International Congress of Eugenics -- First Congress; International Congress of Genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1909-1910 (Box 87)
    - Folder 2, 1911-1912 (Box 87)
    - Folder 3, 1913-1920 (Box 87)
  - Spaeth, Reynold A. (Box 87)
  - Spaulding, Edith R. (Box 87)
  - Spaulding, Volney M. (Box 87)
  - Spemann, Hans (Box 87)
  - Spencer, Henry James (Box 87)
  - Spencer, Mrs. Henry James (Box 87)
  - Spencer, R. R. (Box 87)
  - Spenkman, Horace B. (Box 87)
  - Sperry, Willard L. (Box 87)
  - Spicer, Robert T. (Box 87)
  - Spiller, William A. (Box 87)
  - Spillman, W. J. (Box 87)
  - Spivak, John L. (Box 87)
  - Spoehr, H. A. (Box 87)
  - Spohr, Adelaide A. (Box 87)
  - Spragg, Frank A. (Box 87)
  - Sprague, O. M. W. (Box 87)
  - Springer, Julius (Box 87)
  - Spring-Rice, Sir Cecil Arthur (Box 87)
  - Sproul, William C. (Box 87)
  - Sprunt, Douglas (Box 87)
  - Stach, Johann (Box 87)
  - Staley, William L (Box 87)
  - Standfuss, E. (Box 87)
  - Standfuss, M. (Box 87)
  - Stanka, Hugo (Box 87)
  - Stanley, William (Box 87)
  - Stanton, Hazel M., 1919-1934; 3 folders (101 items) (Box 87)
    Graduate study; Human genetics -- Musical capacity; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1919-1920 (Box 87)
    - Folder 2, 1921-1926 (Box 87)
    - Folder 3, 1929-1934 (Box 87)
  - Stanton, L. W. (Box 87)
  - Stanton, T. W. (Box 87)
  - Station for Experimental Evolution. Whitman material on biological farm. Received from O. Riddle (Box 87)
  - Stebbins, Joel (Box 87)
  - Stechert, G. E., and Co. (Box 87)
  - Stefansson, Vilhjammar (Box 87)
  - Steggarda, Dr. (Box 87)
  - Stein, Calvert (Box 87)
  - Stein, Robert (Box 87)
  - Stephens, T. C. (Box 87)
  - Stephenson, J. C. (Box 87)
  - Stern, Curt (Box 87)
  - Stevens, F. L. (Box 87)
  - Stevens, Joseph T. (Box 87)
  - Stevens, N. M. (Box 87)
  - Stevens, W. L. (Box 87)
  - Stevenson, George H. (Box 87)
  - Stewart, Mary S. (Box 87)
  - Stickney, R. W. (Box 87)
  - Stiles, C. W. (Box 87)
  - Stiles, Walter C. (Box 87)
  - Stillman, Edgar (Box 87)
  - Stinson, V. N. (Box 87)
  - Stobel, William (Box 87)
  - Stober, J. B. (Box 87)
  - Stockard, Charles R. (Box 87)
  - Stoddard, George D. (Box 87)
  - Stoddard, Lothrop (Box 87)
  - Stokes, John H. (Box 87)
  - Stoller, James H. (Box 87)
  - Stomps, Theodore (Box 87)
  - Stone, Calvin P. (Box 87)
  - Stone, Edna L. (Box 87)
  - Storrs, Harry C. (Box 87)
  - Stout, A .B. (Box 87)
  - Stowell, T. B. (Box 87)
  - Straight, Mrs. Willard (Box 88)
  - Strauss, William L., Jr. (Box 88)
  - Streeter, George L., 1919-1933; 3 folders (67 items) (Box 88)
    Academic freedom; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Embryology, developmental genetics; Genetics; Human genetics; Recommendations; Requests for aid in finding positions; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1919-1923 (Box 88)
    - Folder 2, 1924-1929 (Box 88)
    - Folder 3, 1930-1933 (Box 88)
  - Strong, Leonell C. (Box 88)
  - Strong, R. M. (Box 88)
  - Strong, Richard P. (Box 88)
  - Stuart, Mrs. Nelle G. (Box 88)
  - Studebaker, John W. (Box 88)
  - Sturtevant, A. H. (Box 88)
  - Suchetet, A. (Box 88)
  - Suffolk Bulletin (Huntington, N.Y.) (Box 88)
  - Suffolk County Citizen's Committee on Mosquito Elimination (Box 88)
  - Suk, V. (Box 88)
  - Sullivan, Louis R (Box 88)
  - Sullivan, Mrs. Louis R (Bessie Pathers) (Box 88)
  - Summy, B. W. (Box 88)
  - Sumner, Francis B. (Box 88)
  - Sumner, John S. (Box 88)
  - Survey (Box 88)
  - Surveying applications (Box 88)
  - Sutton, Harvey (Box 88)
  - Suziyama, S. (Box 88)
  - Swain, Joseph (Box 88)
  - Swallow, Edward (Box 88)
  - Swingle, W. W. (Wilbur Willis), 1921-1930; 62 items (Box 88)
    Embryology, developmental genetics; Human genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching -- Princeton University
  - Swoboda, Hermann (Box 88)
  - Sykes, G. F. (Box 88)
  - Sylvester, C. B. (Box 88)
  - Symonds, Percival M. (Box 88)
  - Takahashi, Katashi (Box 88)
  - Tan, Chia-Chen (Box 88)
  - Tappone, Victor E. (Box 88)
  - Taufflieb, Mme General (Box 88)
  - Taussig, F. W. (Box 88)
  - Taussig, Fred (Box 88)
  - Taxpayer's League of Oyster Bay Township, 7 folders (Box 88-89)
    - Folder 1 (Box 88)
    - Folder 2 (Box 88)
    - Folder 3 (Box 88)
    - Folder 4 (Box 88)
    - Folder 5 (Box 88)
    - Folder 6 (Box 89)
    - Citizen's Joint Beach Committee (Box 89)
  - Taylor, Charles A. (Box 89)
  - Taylor, Charles K. (Box 89)
  - Taylor, Griffith (Box 89)
  - Taylor, Henry Ling (Box 89)
  - Taylor, J. Madison (Box 89)
  - Taylor, W. R. (Box 89)
  - Tellefron, Marjorie A. (Box 89)
  - Templin, Olin (Box 89)
  - Tennent, D. H. (Box 89)
  - Tenney, A. A. (Box 89)
  - Tenney, A. C. (Box 89)
  - Tenny, C. W. (Box 89)
  - Terman, Louis M. (Box 89)
  - Terry, Robert J., 1911-1930; 2 folders (62 items) (Box 89)
    Anthropology; Eugenics; Human genetics; Reviews; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Solicitations for support or contribution; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Thayer, William Roscoe (Box 89)
  - Thom, William Taylor (Box 89)
  - Thomas, Wilbur (Box 89)
  - Thomas William Salmon Memorial, Inc. (Box 89)
  - Thompson, Charles H. (Box 89)
  - Thompson, George L. (Box 89)
  - Thompson, W. O. (Box 89)
  - Thomson, Elihu (Box 89)
  - Thomson, J. Arthur (Box 89)
  - Thomson, Lee W. (Box 89)
  - Thomson, Mary J. (Box 89)
  - Thorn, Frank B. (Box 89)
  - Thorndike, E. L. (Edward L.), 1901-1930; 57 items (Box 89)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Eugenics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Tietze, Felix (Box 89)
  - Tiffany, Mrs. Charles L. (Box 89)
  - Tiffany, H. G. (Box 89)
  - Tiffany, Louis C. (Box 89)
  - Tiffany, William J. (Box 89)
  - Tillett, Kate S. (Box 89)
  - Tilney, Frederick (Box 89)
  - Tilson, John Q. (Box 89)
  - Tilton, Mrs. William (Box 89)
  - Timanus, G. L. (Box 89)
  - Time. Editor (Box 89)
  - Timm, Edward G. (Box 89)
  - Timme, Walter (Box 89)
  - Timme, Mrs. Walter (Box 89)
  - Timoféeff-Ressovsky, N. W. (Box 89)
  - Tingey, D. C. (Box 89)
  - Tinkle, William J. (Box 89)
  - Tirrill Gas Machine Lighting Co. (Box 89)
  - Tisdale, W. H. (Box 89)
  - Titus, Charles P. (Box 89)
  - Titus, Edward V. (Box 89)
  - Titus, Helen (Box 89)
  - Titus, William W. (Box 89)
  - Tobler, F. (Box 89)
  - Todd, T. Wingate, 1922-1932; 3 folders (93 items) (Box 89)
    Anthropology; Conferences and symposia; Embryology, developmental genetics; Eugenics; Human genetics; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1922-1926 (Box 89)
    - Folder 2, 1927-1929 (Box 89)
    - Folder 3, 1930-1932 (Box 89)
  - Toll, Henry W. (Box 89)
  - Tolman, Edward C. (Box 89)
  - Tomoyama, Sanroo (Box 89)
  - Toops, Herbert A. (Box 89)
  - Torrance, Arthur (Box 89)
  - Torrey, J. C. (Box 89)
  - Torrey, Raymond H. (Box 89)
  - Tortugas Laboratory (Box 90)
  - Tower, R. W. (Ralph W.), 1904-1925; 62 items (Box 90)
    Bibliographical matters; Committee activities; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Tower, William L., 1898-1917; 3 folders (108 items) (Box 90)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Genetics; Graduate study; Human genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Zoology
    - Folder 1, 1898-1904 (Box 90)
    - Folder 2, 1905-1906 (Box 90)
    - Folder 3, 1907-1917 (Box 90)
  - Townsend, Charles H. (Box 90)
  - Tozzer, A. M. (Box 90)
  - Training School at Vineland, NJ (Box 90)
  - Transeau, E. N. (Box 90)
  - Treadway, Walter L. (Box 90)
  - Tredgold, A. F. (Box 90)
  - Trexler, T. Bertrand (Box 90)
  - Trotter, Mildred (Box 90)
  - True, A. C. (Box 90)
  - True, F. W. (Box 90)
  - True, Rodney H. (Box 90)
  - Trüebner, Karl J. (Box 90)
  - Tsamados, M. (Box 90)
  - Tschermak-Seysenegg, Armin (Box 90)
  - Tschermak-Seysenegg, Erich von, 1904-1932; 70 items (Box 90)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; History of biology, especially genetics -- Mendel, Gregor; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Tsubina, E. (Box 90)
  - Tubbs, Anne Bartlett (Box 90)
  - Tubby, Gertrude Ogden (Box 90)
  - Tubby, William B. (Box 90)
  - Tuck, Charles H. (Box 90)
  - Tucker, Margaret (Box 90)
  - Tucker, W. R. (Box 90)
  - Tufts College, Boston (Box 90)
  - Tulane University (Box 90)
  - Tullock, George S. (Box 90)
  - Turck, Fenton (Box 90)
  - Turesson, Göte (Box 90)
  - Turnbull, C. J. (Box 90)
  - Turner, C. L. (Box 90)
  - Turner, Edgar C. (Box 90)
  - Turner, Joseph (Box 90)
  - Tuskegee Institute (Box 90)
  - Tweedie, Alexander R. (Box 90)
  - Twichell, George E. (Box 90)
  - Twichell, Pierrepont E. (Box 90)
  - Twins (Heredity) (Box 90)
  - Twins (Relative), 2 folders (Box 90)
  - Twitmyer, Edwin B. (Box 90)
  - Tyler, Comfort A. (Box 90)
  - Tyler, H. W. (Box 90)
  - Tyler, W. S. & Co. (Box 90)
  - Tyree, Sally (Box 90)
  - Tyson, Francis D. (Box 90)
  - Tyzzer, Dr. (Box 90)
  - Uber, J. E. (Box 91)
  - Udell, Maida E. (Box 91)
  - Uhlenhuth, E. (Box 91)
  - Ulbrich, Josaf (Box 91)
  - Underhill, Francis T. (Box 91)
  - Underhill, Ida F. (Box 91)
  - Underwood, O. W. (Box 91)
  - United States (Box 91)
    - United States. Army. Office of the Surgeon General, 1907-1929; 5 folders (Box 91)
      Anthropology; World War I -- Impact on science
    - United States. Consular Service (Box 91)
    - United States. Customs Service (Box 91)
    - United States. Department of Agriculture, 3 folders (Box 91)
      - United States. Dept. of Agriculture. Bureau of Plant Industry (Box 91)
      - United States. Dept. of Agriculture. Forest Service (Box 91)
      - United States. Dept. of Agriculture. Weather Bureau (Box 91)
    - United States. Department of State (Box 91)
    - United States. Eastern Federal Judicial District (Box 91)
    - United States. Government Printing Office (Box 91)
    - United States. Immigration Authority (Box 91)
      In re. Curt Stern.
    - United States. President (Box 91)
    - United States. War Department. Bureau of Insular Affairs (Box 91)
  - University of Adelaide (Box 91)
  - University of Cambridge. Commemoration of Charles Darwin (Box 91)
  - University of Chicago, 9 folders (Box 91-92)
    - Alumni Club of New York City (Box 91)
    - Attendance books, 2 books (Box 92)
    - Notes: Chickens - early reports (Box 92)
    - Notes: Chickens - ovaries (Box 92)
    - Notes: Descriptions of Poultry, 1904 (Box 92)
    - Notes: Geographical Distribution (Box 92)
    - Notes: Pecten, 1900 - (Box 92)
    - Notes: Pecten Charts (Box 92)
    - Notes: Variation (Box 92)
    - Notes: "Where the River Meets the Sea", 1903, November (Box 92)
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 91)
  - Unknown (Box 91)
  - Valentine, J. W. (Box 91)
  - Van Schelle, A. (Box 91)
  - Vanamee, Mrs. William (Box 91)
  - Vanderlip, Frank A. (Box 91)
  - Varrelman, F. A. (Box 91)
  - Vaughan, T. Wayland (Box 91)
  - Vaughan, Victor C. (Box 91)
  - Vauttise, Charles R. (Box 91)
  - Vavilov, N. (Box 91)
  - Vermont Agricultural Station (Box 91)
  - Vernon, H. M. (Box 91)
  - Vernon, Townsend (Box 91)
  - Verrill, A. G. (Box 91)
  - Verscluys, J. (Box 91)
  - Verzár, Frederic (Box 91)
  - Victor, Joseph (Box 91)
  - Victoreen Instrument Company (Box 91)
  - Vieth, George J. (Box 91)
  - Vijaya-Tunga, J. (Box 91)
  - Vilmorin, Jacques De (Box 91)
  - Vincent, George E. (Box 91)
  - Vinson, Robert E. (Box 91)
  - Viola, H. E. (Box 91)
  - Vir publishing company (Box 91)
  - Virksen, Edward (Box 91)
  - Virkus, Fred A. (Box 91)
  - Vitale, Alfredo (Box 91)
  - Vitelli, G. (Box 91)
  - Vogodskaja, Z. (Box 91)
  - Vogt, Prof. (Box 91)
  - Vogt, Walther (Box 91)
  - Voigtländer and Sohn (Box 91)
  - Volta Bureau (Box 91)
  - Voss, H. E. (Box 91)
  - Vossius, Dr. (Box 91)
  - Vries, Hugo de, 1904-1936; 2 folders (56 items) (Box 93)
    Biographical and personal data -- Vries, Hugo de; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Genetics of plants; Poultry genetics; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Waada, B.. (Box 93)
  - Waardenburg, P. J. (Box 93)
  - Wächter, W. (Box 93)
  - Wachter, W. L. (Box 93)
  - Waddell, R. W. (Box 93)
  - Wade, Frank B. (Box 93)
  - Wade, W. O. (Box 93)
  - Wadley, M. E. (Box 93)
  - Wadsworth, Alice Emily (Box 93)
  - Wadsworth, James W., Jr. (Box 93)
  - Wadsworth, Mrs. H. H. (Box 93)
  - Wadsworth, William B. (Box 93)
  - Wagenhals, Margaret (Box 93)
  - Wagenseil, F. (Box 93)
  - Wagner Bros. and Co. (Box 93)
  - Wagner, Julia G. (Box 93)
  - Wainwright, John W. (Box 93)
  - Waite, Mary L. (Box 93)
  - Walcott, Charles Doolittle, 1903-1927; 4 folders (165 items) (Box 93)
    Biographical and personal data; Burbank, Luther; Business; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Conferences and symposia; Publication; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; World War I -- Impact on science
    - Folders 1-3, 1903-1904; 3 folders (Box 93)
    - Folder 4, 1908-1927 (Box 93)
  - Walcott, Frederic (Box 93)
  - Walcott, Gregory D. (Box 93)
  - Waldron, L. R. (Box 93)
  - Walker, Clifford (Box 93)
  - Walker, Frank N. (Box 93)
  - Walker, Helen M. (Box 93)
  - Wallace, James L. (Box 93)
  - Walter, Alice Hall (Box 93)
  - Walter, Frank K. (Box 93)
  - Walter, H. E. (Box 93)
  - Walters, Henry G. (Box 93)
  - Ward, C. W. (Box 93)
  - Ward, Frank A. (Box 93)
  - Ward, Henry B., 1891-1940; 6 folders (204 items) (Box 93)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Editorial matters; Educational matters; Eugenics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Zoology
    - Folder 1, 1891-1899 (Box 93)
    - Folder 2, 1900-1906 (Box 93)
    - Folder 3, 1907-1911 (Box 93)
    - Folder 4, 1912-1920 (Box 93)
    - Folder 5, 1921-1925 (Box 93)
    - Folder 6, 1926-1940 (Box 93)
  - Warren, D. C. (Box 93)
  - Warren, James (Box 93)
  - Warren, Joseph H. (Box 93)
  - Warwick, B. L. (Box 93)
  - Washburn, F. L. (Box 93)
  - Washington, Booker T. (Box 93)
  - Watase, Shozaburo (Box 94)
  - Waterfall, Myrtle H. (Box 94)
  - Waters, Arthur William (Box 94)
  - Waters, H. J. (Box 94)
  - Waters, Nelson F. (Box 94)
  - Watson, J. M. (Box 94)
  - Watson, John B. (Box 94)
  - Watson, Lloyd R. (Box 94)
  - Watson, Mrs. F. D. (Box 94)
  - Watters, C. N. (Box 94)
  - Watterson, Ada (Box 94)
  - Weaver, Rufus Lee (Box 94)
  - Weaver, Warren (Box 94)
  - Webber, Hubert J. (Box 94)
  - Weber, Samuel E. (Box 94)
  - Webster, F. M. (Box 94)
  - Wechsler, David (Box 94)
  - Weed, Howard Evarts (Box 94)
  - Weed, LeRoy J. (Box 94)
  - Weeks, Henry Clay (Box 94)
  - Weidenreich, Franz (Box 94)
  - Weismann, Aug. (Box 94)
  - Weitzner, Bella (Box 94)
  - Welch, William H. (Box 94)
  - Weld, D. C., Jr. (Box 94)
  - Weldon, W. T. B. (Box 94)
  - Wells, Clifford W. (Box 94)
  - Wells, H. Gideon (Box 94)
  - Weltner, W. (Box 94)
  - Went, F. A. F. C. (Box 94)
  - Wentworth, Edward N. (Box 94)
  - Werbeck, Marie (Box 94)
  - Westgate, J. M. (Box 94)
  - Whatham, Arthur E. (Box 94)
  - Wheeler, W. P. (Box 94)
  - Wheeler, William Morton (Box 94)
  - Wheldale, Muriel (Box 94)
  - Whipple, George C. (Box 94)
  - Whipple, Leon (Box 94)
  - Whitaker, Alfred E. (Box 94)
  - White, David: N.A.S. Committee on Biographical Memoirs. (Box 94)
  - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection, 1929-1930; 9 folders (Box 94)
    Committee activities; Conferences and symposia
    - Folders 1-4 (Box 94)
    - Blackfan, Kenneth D. (Box 94)
    - Davis, Hallowell (Box 94)
    - Hamill, Samuel McC. (Box 94)
    - Stuart, Harold C. (Box 94)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman (Box 94)
  - White, O. E. (Box 94)
  - White, William A. (Box 94)
  - Whitford, H. N. (Box 94)
  - Whitin, E. Stagg (Box 94)
  - Whiting, Anna R. (Box 94)
  - Whiting, P. W. (Phineas Westcott) (Box 94)
  - Whitman, Charles Otis, 1891-1916; 31 folders (Box 95)
    Biographical and personal data; Biological Farm Project; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole
    - Biography, 1916 (Box 95)
    - Biological Farm Project, 1896-1909; 7 folders (Box 95)
      - Biological Farm Project (Box 95)
      - C. B. Davenport (Box 95)
      - Roswell H. Johnson (Box 95)
      - H. P. Judson (Box 95)
      - R. Meldola (Box 95)
      - L. H. Plate (Box 95)
      - Rollin D. Salisbury (Box 95)
    - Woods Hole Correspondence, 1891-1892; 23 folders (Box 95)
      - A. Agassiz (Box 95)
      - R. Blanchard (Box 95)
      - Samuel F. Clarke (Box 95)
      - Anton Dohry (Box 95)
      - William Gilson Farlowe (Box 95)
      - S. A. Forbes (Box 95)
      - M. Foster (Box 95)
      - Simon H. Gage (Box 95)
      - Carl Gegenbaur (Box 95)
      - Ernst Haeckel (Box 95)
      - G. B. Howes (Box 95)
      - Thomas Henry Huxley (Box 95)
      - David Starr Jordan (Box 95)
      - Edwin Ray Lankester (Box 95)
      - Rudulf Leuckart (Box 95)
      - William Libbey (Box 95)
      - C. Ludwig (Box 95)
      - Albert Philip Ohlmacher (Box 95)
      - Herbert Spencer (Box 95)
      - William Trelease (Box 95)
      - Carl Vogt (Box 95)
      - August Weismann (Box 95)
      - Edmund B. Wilson (Box 95)
  - Whitman, Charles S. (Box 95)
  - Whitman, Mrs. Charles O. (Box 95)
  - Whitney, D. D. (Box 95)
  - Whitney, J. A. (Box 95)
  - Whitney, Leon F., 4 folders (Box 95)
    - Folders 1-2, 1928; 2 folders (Box 95)
    - Folders 3-4, 1929-1932; 2 folders (Box 95)
  - Whitney, Willis Rodney (Box 95)
  - Wickham, Mr. (Box 95)
  - Wiedersherm, R. (Box 95)
  - Wigmore, John H. (Box 95)
  - Wiking, Sven (Box 95)
  - Wilcox, E. Mead (Box 95)
  - Wilcox, Walter F. (Box 95)
  - Wilcrynsk, J. (Box 95)
  - Wild, Maria (Box 95)
  - Wilder, Harris Hawthorne, 1901-1927; 3 folders (77 items) (Box 95)
    Anthropology; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Eugenics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching
    - Folder 1, 1901-1908 (Box 95)
    - Folder 2, 1919 (Box 95)
    - Folder 3, 1920-1927 (Box 95)
  - Wilder, Inez Whipple (Box 95)
  - Wile, Ira S. (Box 95)
  - Wile, Udo J. (Box 95)
  - Willard, F. C. (Box 95)
  - Willcox, M. A. (Box 95)
  - Willcox, Walter F. (Box 95)
  - Willets, E. H. (Box 95)
  - Williams and Wilkins Co., 2 folders (Box 95)
  - Williams, Digan (Box 95)
  - Williams, J. B. (Box 95)
  - Williams, J. Harold (Box 95)
  - Williams, John S. (Box 95)
  - Williams, Mrs. L. M. (Box 95)
  - Williams, L. W. (Box 95)
  - Williams, Mrs. Vay H. (Box 95)
  - Williams, R. H. (Box 95)
  - Williams, Spalding (Box 95)
  - Williams, Stephen R. (Box 95)
  - Williamson, Cornelia (Box 96)
  - Williamson, H. L. (Box 96)
  - Willis, Charles A. (Box 96)
  - Williston, S. N. (Box 96)
  - Willoby, Charles H. (Box 96)
  - Willoughby, Raymond R. (Box 96)
  - Willson, Glentworth M. (Box 96)
  - Wilmanns, Dr. (Box 96)
  - Wilson, Edmund Beecher, 1897-1932; 2 folders (53 items) (Box 96)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Genetics; Publication; Recommendations; Zoology
  - Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1914-1941; 4 folders (175 items) (Box 96)
    Bibliographical matters; Editorial matters; National Academy of Sciences; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Folder 1, 1914-1915 (Box 96)
    - Folder 2, 1916-1928 (Box 96)
    - Folder 3, 1929-1934 (Box 96)
    - Folder 4, 1935-1941 (Box 96)
  - Wilson, H. M. (Box 96)
  - Wilson, H. V. (Box 96)